Guide to the William J. Roege Photograph Collection 1910-1937, undated PR 181
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Negatives
  - Film Negatives - 8 x 10 inches
    - Pennsylvania Railroad locomotives, Hudson Co., New Jersey, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9091)
    - Pulaski Skyway over the Hackensack River, New Jersey, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9092)
    - Westchester Avenue, Bronx, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9093)
      [Copy negative of ca. 1900 original]
    - Willis Avenue and 148th Street, 1930 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9094)
    - Kingsbridge Road, looking northeast from Fordham Road, Bronx, 1930 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9095)
    - Kingsbridge Road, "Original site of Poe House", Bronx, 1930 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9096)
    - Queensboro Bridge and Franklin D. Roosevelt Island, [1925] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9097)
    - Allen Street, north from Division Street, 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9098)
    - U.S. Customs House, [1930] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9099)
    - Broadway, 88-96, at Wall Street, 1928, 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9100-9101)
    - Church Street, from St. Paul's Chapel to Barclay Street, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9102)
    - City Hall Park, [1930] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9103)
    - East Broadway, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9104)
    - Nassau Street from Pine to Wall Streets, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9105)
    - 1920 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9106)
    - Pearl Street, 171-205, [1929] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9107)
    - Pearl Street, 169-181, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9108)
    - Wall Street, west from William Street, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9109)
    - Wall Street, between Hanover and William Streets, 1935 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9110)
    - Washington Street, west side between Morris Street and Battery Place, 1928 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9111)
    - West Street at and south of Morris Street, 1928 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9112)
    - Third Avenue and 41st Street, northeast corner, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9113)
    - Fifth Avenue, from 45th to 59th Streets, 1925-1935, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9115-9124)
    - Seventh Avenue, south from 36th Street, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9125)
    - Seventh Avenue, south from 38th Street, 1924 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9126-9127)
    - Eighth Avenue, west side from 31st to 33rd Streets, including U.S. Post Office, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9128)
    - Broadway, south from Columbus Circle, 1933 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9129)
    - Bryant Park, during Washington Bicentennial, 1932 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9130)
    - Lexington Avenue, 42nd to 47th Streets, 1928, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9131-9132)
    - Madison Square Park, 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9133)
    - West 23rd Street, 409-523, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9134)
    - West 23rd Street, 361-363, 1928 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9135)
    - 23rd Street, north side, east from west of Fifth Avenue, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9136)
    - Grand Central Terminal, 1934, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9137-9138)
    - West 44th Street, from east of Fifth Avenue, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9140)
    - West 44th Street, 53-65, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9141)
    - New York Bar Association, West 44th Street, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9142)
    - New York Yacht Club, West 44th Street, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9143)
    - West 54th Street, west from Fifth Avenue, 1928 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9145)
    - Mecca Temple [Masonic], 131-135 West 55th Street, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9146)
    - Calvary Baptist Church, West 57th Street, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9147)
    - West 57th Street, east from and including Sixth Avenue, 1928 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9148)
    - Holy Trinity Lutheran Church, Central Park West and 65th Street, 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9149)
    - Central Park West between 69th and 70th Streets, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9150)
    - Hotel Majestic, Central Park West, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9151)
    - Columbus Circle, 1921 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9152-9153)
    - Grant's Tomb, Riverside Drive from 122nd Street, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9154)
    - International House, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9155)
    - Madison Avenue, looking north from 61st Street, 1928 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9156)
    - Fifth Avenue at 61st Street, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9157)
    - Temple Emanu-El, Fifth Avenue and 65th Street, [1930-1935] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9158-9159)
    - Fifth Avenue from 78th to 101st Street, 1927-1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9160-9168)
    - Pulitzer Residence, 7 East 73rd Street, 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9169)
    - Farmers Trust Co. Building, William Street, 1934 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9170-9171)
    - RCA Building, Rockefeller Center, [1933] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9172)
    - West 46th Street, 68-74, includes Hotel Richmond, [1915] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9402)
    - Rockefeller Center Plaza, looking north from 49th Street, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9415)
  - Film Negatives (Damaged) - 8 x 10 inches
    - W.O.R. Broadcasting Station, Newark, New Jersey, 1934 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9090)
    - Pennsylvania Railroad locomotives, Hudson Co., New Jersey, 1934 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9091)
    - Church Street, from St. Paul's Chapel to Barclay Street, 1934 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9102)
    - Wall Street, between Hanover and William Streets, 1935 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9110)
    - West 44th Street, 53-65, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9141)
  - Film Negatives - 11 x 14 inches
    - Wentworth Hotel, West 46th Street (66618-D), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9403)
    - Fifth Avenue, east side, between 48th and 49th Streets (66619-D), 1924 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9407)
    - St. Patrick's Cathedral (66620-D), 1934 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9414)
    - Fifth Avenue, east side, between 56th and 55th Streets (66616-D), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9418)
    - Fifth Avenue, west side, looking south from 58th Street (66617-D), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9419)
    - Fifth Avenue, Grand Army Plaza and General William Tecumseh Sherman statue (66621-D), 1923 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9422)
    - Broadway and Seventh Avenue, looking south (66622-D), 1923 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9437)
  - Glass Negatives - 5 x 7 inches
    - Park Row and City Hall Park, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 9019)
    - Tenth Avenue, east side between 43rd and 44th Streets, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 9020)
    - West 38th Street [Copy negative after 1922 original], undated (Box 7, Folder 9021)
  - Glass Negatives - 8 x 10 inches
    - Niagara Falls, undated (Box 7, Folder 9173-9174)
    - S.S. Antilles, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 9175)
    - German ocean liners interned during World War I at Hoboken, New Jersey, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 9176)
    - East River, Franklin D. Roosevelt Island, and 65th-72nd Streets, undated (Box 7, Folder 9177)
    - Grand Concourse near 162nd Street, east side, undated (Box 7, Folder 9178)
    - Allen Street from Canal Street north to Delancey Street, 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 9179-9182)
    - Fifth Avenue near 8th Street, looking south to Washington Square Arch, [1921] (Box 7, Folder 9183)
    - Fifth Avenue and Broadway including the Flatiron Building, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 9184)
    - Fifth Avenue, Police parade, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 9185-9188)
    - New York Public Library, [1912] (Box 7, Folder 9189)
    - Fifth Avenue at W. 48th to 49th Streets, [1934] (Box 7, Folder 9190)
    - Fifth Avenue, rooftop view to south at 51st Street, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 9191)
    - Plaza Hotel, [1927] (Box 7, Folder 9192)
    - Sixth Avenue, looking north from 48th Street, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 9193)
    - Eighth Avenue and 42nd Street, northwest corner, undated (Box 7, Folder 9194-9195)
    - Astor Hotel, Broadway at 45th Street, [1925] (Box 7, Folder 9196)
    - Broadway and Seventh Avenue, south from 44th Street, [1918] (Box 8, Folder 9197)
    - Madison Square Park, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 9198)
    - Union Square, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 9199)
    - West 15th Street, north side from Fifth Avenue, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 9200)
    - East 23rd Street at Madison Square Park, [1922] (Box 8, Folder 9201)
    - West 34th Street, south side from Seventh to Fifth Avenue, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 9202)
    - West 38th Street, from Seventh to Fifth Avenue, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 9204)
    - West 42nd Street, looking west from Seventh Avenue, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 9205)
    - Grand Central Terminal, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 9206)
    - 42nd Street, north side between Lexington and Grand Central Terminal, undated (Box 8, Folder 9207)
    - Hotel Langwell, 123-129 West 44th Street, [1922] (Box 8, Folder 9208)
    - East 44th Street, north side, from Fifth to Vanderbilt Avenue, [1928] (Box 8, Folder 9209)
    - West 56th Street, 317-339, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 9210)
    - West 57th Street and Seventh Avenue, undated (Box 8, Folder 9211)
    - Riverside Drive, double-decker bus, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 9212)
    - Grant's Tomb and Riverside Drive, [1924] (Box 8, Folder 9213)
    - Hotel Alexandria, West 103rd Street, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 9214)
    - Fifth Avenue, looking north from 69th Street, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 9215)
    - Fifth Avenue between 49th and 50th Street, fountain, [1934] (Box 8, Folder 9216)
    - Warren Street, undated (Box 8, Folder 9217)
      [Copy negative of a lithograph by W. Stephenson & Co., New York]
    - Charles R. Lohman Residence, 657 Fifth Avenue, undated (Box 8, Folder 9218)
      [Copy negative of a lithograph by Hatch & Co.]
    - Madison Avenue, 182, undated (Box 8, Folder 9219)
      [Copy negative of halftone]
    - Fifth Avenue, east side from 59th to 58th Street, undated (Box 8, Folder 9220)
    - "The Plaza", undated (Box 8, Folder 9221)
    - Beekman Street, east from Park Row, undated (Box 8, Folder 9222)
      [Copy negative]
    - Bowery, 131-133, undated (Box 8, Folder 9223)
      [Copy negative of 1868 original]
    - Broadway, aerial view, undated (Box 8, Folder 9224)
    - Broadway, from Fulton to Bleecker Street, undated (Box 9, Folder 9225-9231)
      [Copy negatives]
    - Rooftop view to north from Centre Street, undated (Box 9, Folder 9232)
    - Hudson River, looking west from Trinity Church spire, undated (Box 9, Folder 9233)
    - Chatham Square, north side and Bowery, undated (Box 9, Folder 9234)
    - Park Row and City Hall Park, undated (Box 9, Folder 9235-9238)
    - Henry Street, 202-206, undated (Box 9, Folder 9239)
    - John Street, north side from Nassau Street, undated (Box 9, Folder 9240)
    - South Ferry, undated (Box 9, Folder 9241)
    - South Street, undated (Box 9, Folder 9242-9243)
    - Fourth Avenue, north across 7th Street, undated (Box 9, Folder 9244)
    - Union Square East, rooftop view, undated (Box 9, Folder 9245)
    - Union Clubhouse, Fifth Avenue and 21st Street, undated (Box 9, Folder 9247)
    - Fifth Avenue from 28th to 60th Streets, undated (Box 9, Folder 9248-9254)
    - Broadway, from 43rd to 59th Streets, undated (Box 10, Folder 9255-9257)
    - East 14th Street, looking west, showing Tammany Hall, undated (Box 10, Folder 9258)
      [Copy negative of ca. 1914 photographs]
    - West 23rd Street and Eighth Avenue, Grand Opera House, undated (Box 10, Folder 9259)
    - East 23rd Street and Lexington Avenue, undated (Box 10, Folder 9260)
    - West 44th Street, undated (Box 10, Folder 9261)
    - West 54th Street and Fifth Avenue, undated (Box 10, Folder 9262)
    - Grant's Tomb, Riverside Drive, men in navy uniforms in buses, undated (Box 10, Folder 9263)
      [Copy negative of a 1917 original]
    - Central Park, undated (Box 10, Folder 9264)
    - Central Park, undated (Box 10, Folder 9266)
      [Copy negative from ca. 1920 photograph]
    - Fifth Avenue and 87th Street, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 9267)
    - Fort Washington Avenue "Boss Tweed's Country Home", undated (Box 10, Folder 9268)
    - East 149th Street and Third Avenue, Bronx, undated (Box 10, Folder 9269)
    - Third Avenue at 148th Street, Bronx, undated (Box 10, Folder 9270)
    - Lower Manhattan from the Hudson River, downtown, undated (Box 10, Folder 9271)
      [Copy negative of ca. 1920 photograph]
    - Jumel Mansion, interior, undated (Box 10, Folder 9272)
    - AT&T Building, detail of statue Golden Boy at top of building, undated (Box 10, Folder 9273)
    - Europe, statue, undated (Box 10, Folder 9274)
    - Unidentified eagle statue, undated (Box 10, Folder 9276)
    - Broad Street, looking north from Exchange Place, undated (Box 10, Folder 9277)
    - Broadway and Bowling Green, undated (Box 10, Folder 9278)
    - Trinity Churchyard, undated (Box 10, Folder 9279)
      [Copy negative of 1928 Roege photograph]
    - Park Place, undated (Box 10, Folder 9280)
      [Copy negative of 1910 Roege photograph]
    - Wall Street between Nassau and William Streets, undated (Box 10, Folder 9281)
    - West Street, undated (Box 10, Folder 9282)
    - Park Avenue, west side from 47th to 49th Streets, undated (Box 10, Folder 9283)
      [Copy negative of 1921 original]
    - Fifth Avenue at 13th Street, undated (Box 11, Folder 9284)
      [Copy negative of 1920 original]
    - Fifth Avenue, looking north from 27th Street, undated (Box 11, Folder 9285)
      [Copy negative of ca. 1865 photograph]
    - Fifth Avenue at 34th Street, undated (Box 11, Folder 9286)
      [Copy negative of ca. 1917 original]
    - Fifth Avenue, looking south from 42nd Street, undated (Box 11, Folder 9287)
      [Copy negative of 1880 original]
    - Fifth Avenue, west side, north from 42nd Street, undated (Box 11, Folder 9288)
      [Copy negative of 1914 original]
    - Black, Starr & Front Building, Fifth Avenue at 48th Street, undated (Box 11, Folder 9289)
    - Seventh Avenue at Times Square, undated (Box 11, Folder 9290)
      [Copy negative of 1916 photograph]
    - Broadway and Sixth Avenue, undated (Box 11, Folder 9291)
    - Times Square, undated (Box 11, Folder 9292)
    - East 42nd Street and Lexington Avenue, undated (Box 11, Folder 9293)
    - 43rd Street, north side, east across Broadway, undated (Box 11, Folder 9294)
    - Bretton Hall, undated (Box 11, Folder 9295)
      [Copy negative of 1910 original]
    - Riverside Drive at 100th Street, undated (Box 11, Folder 9296)
    - Stock broker's office, interior, undated (Box 11, Folder 9297)
    - Consolidated Exchange, undated (Box 11, Folder 9298)
  - Glass Negatives - 11 x 14 inches
    - Hotel Prince George (66627-D), undated (Box 12, Folder 9354)
    - Hotel Alcazar (66631-D), undated (Box 12, Folder 9359)
    - Grand Central Terminal, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 9377)
    - Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, Fifth Avenue from 34th Street (66629-D), [1920] (Box 12, Folder 9388)
    - Columbia Theatre (66630-D), undated (Box 12, Folder 9438)
    - Hotel Bristol and Playhouse Theatre (66628-D), undated (Box 12, Folder 9443)
    - Hotel Markwell (66626-D), undated (Box 12, Folder 9445)
    - West 50th Street, 214-234 (66632-D), undated (Box 12, Folder 9447)
    - West 55th Street, west across Seventh Avenue (66643-D), 1912 (Box 12, Folder 9453)
    - West 55th Street, rooftop view to southwest (66641-D), undated (Box 12, Folder 9456)
    - West 55th Street, rooftop view to west (66641-D), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 9457)
    - West 55th Street, rooftop view to northwest (66634-D), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 9458)
    - Park Avenue, 636-648 (66642-D), 1918 (Box 12, Folder 9485)